# ANUPAMA DILSHAN



14 Vicar street, Gilles Plains, Adelaide 5086 Australia +61452575523 anupama.dilshan@icloud.com

# **Professional Summary**

Recent University of Adelaide Computer Science Master's graduate with three years of global experience in software development, specializing in ERP systems, web, mobile development, and machine learning. Dedicated to exceeding standards with exceptional work, I am fully available and eligible for full-time opportunities.

#### Skills

- Java, Python, C, C++, C#, Dart, Kotlin
- Node.is, Express.is, ASP.NET, Laravel, Flask
- · APPIAN BPMS, Salesforce, IFS ERP
- · Kubernetes, Docker, Xamarin

- HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, React, Angular, Ajax, TS
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase
- AWS, GCP, Heroku, Jenkins, GitLab CI

## **Experience**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2022 - Dec 2022

Savvy finance - Norwood, SA, Australia

- Enhanced financial components using Node.js and Salesforce, optimizing performance for client-specific solutions.
- Utilized Bash for scripting and automating tasks, resulting in streamlined development operations.
- Developed and deployed innovative applications using Salesforce Lightning Web Components (LWC) and Apex, significantly enhancing customer capability to capitalize on sales opportunities.
- Participated in customer and project interviews, providing mentorship and expert input on technical strategies.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2020 - Jan 2022

IFS Research & Development (Pvt) Ltd Sri Lanka

- Applied SE principles in C++, C#.NET and PL/SQL for comprehensive application development in IFS ERP.
- Managed cloud data and web server operations on Linux OS, ensuring robust performance, security, and scalability.
- Utilized Oracle databases and PLSQL Developer for efficient data management.
- Orchestrated CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins and Maven, optimizing the software delivery process.

#### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

Sep 2019 - Nov 2019

Devest - Mansoura, Egypt, Egypt

- Transformed Adobe XD UI designs into fully functional and mobile-responsive web applications using PHP and Laravel.
- Developed and managed well-functioning MySQL databases and Rest APIs for the dynamic blog and portofolio.
- Overcame language barriers and applied country specific technology principles (Ex: Right-to-left) in the code.

## FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

Nichelabs (Pvt) Ltd Sri Lanka

- Initiated relational & NoSQL databases and Designed APIs using Express.js, Node.js, GraphQL to allow backend tointeract smoothly with websites.
- Improved frontend using react.js, JavaScript and styling libraries (Boostrap, Tailwind CSS) to enhance user experienceand functionality (Web & mobile friendly)
- Coordinated with QA team to create test plans, properly identifying, fixing, and testing issues.

#### **Education**

 $Master\ of\ Science: Computer\ Science\ (GPA-5.8/7)$ 

Feb 2024

University of Adelaide - Adelaide, SA, Australia

- Awarded the prestigious "Global Citizens Scholarship", covering 30% of tuition fees, in recognition of outstanding academic performance in previous studies.
- Key courses: Distributed systems, Mining Big Data, Applied Machine Learning, Applied Natural Language Processing, Event-Driven computing, Secure Software Engineering, Research Project.

Bachelor of Science : SoftwareEngineering

Curtin University Australia

• Key courses: Operating Systems, Human Computer Interface, Distributed Computing, Programming Languages, Software Engineering Concepts, Software Engineering Testing.

Higher National Diploma(HND): SoftwareEngineering

Dec 2018

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology(SLIIT

• Key courses: Object-oriented programming, Probability & Statistics, Information Systems & Data Modeling, Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Networks, Database Management Systems

## **Projects**

## WeCare mobile app (2023)

- Developed a comprehensive smart home monitoring system aimed at preventing falls and wandering in elderly
  individuals with cognitive impairments.
- Technologies used: Jupyter Notebook, Makefile, Python, Dart, C++, CMake, Flutter, Raspberry Pi Specifics

## CropSense Web app (2023)

- · Created an AI-Generated Content (AIGC) based Leaf Disease Detection Application for agriculture.
- Technologies used: React.JS, NodeJS, Flask, Python, ChatGPTAPI, MongoDB

#### Find Love Matching application (2022)

- · Developed a dating website with security methods implemented
- Technologies used: React.JS, NodeJS, MySQL

#### DEVEST Tech Company Website | Egypt (2020)

- Designed and developed a dynamic, mobile-responsive website for Devest software company, including UX design, frontend and backend implementation with an admin dashboard. Added dynamic blog and portfolio sections.
- Technologies used: Laravel, HTML5, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap, MySQL, Adobe XD

Nichelabs Internal Employee Management system (2021)

- Engineered an internal employee management system
- Technologies used: APPIAN BPMS, PostgreSQL, SOAP

#### MEDIXO Medical Prescription Reader Mobile Application

- Developed a mobile application for reading handwritten medical prescriptions, assisting patients in finding nearby pharmacies and recommending drugs.
- Technologies used: Python, Kotlin, Firebase, Google vision API, Machine learning, Android SDK

#### **DEVENT Event Management Company Website**

• Technologies used: PHP, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL, Netlify

## D & D Builder Fun Game

• Technologies used: ASP.NET, C#, SQLite, Javascript, CSS, XML, CSS, External API

## Volunteering

- Local Committee Vice President, AIESEC in University of Sri Jayewardenepura: Spearheaded team operations and strategic planning, enhancing organizational impact and fostering leadership development within the committee.
- *Team Leader, Project "Be Sri Lanka"*: Led a diverse volunteer team in promoting sustainable tourism and cultural preservation, coordinating with multiple stakeholders and managing project execution.
- Marketing Head, International Congress: Strategized and executed comprehensive marketing campaigns, significantly boosting event visibility and engagement across various digital and traditional platforms.

### accomplishments

- 9th country rank, 3rd state rank for GCE Advanced Levels examination (2016)
- Best Emerging Young Leader (2019) AIESEC in Sri Lanka
- Best Leadership entity in Outgoing Global Talent (2021) AIESEC in Sri Lanka
- Excellence in Outgoing Global Talent (2021) Asia Pacific Region
- Best young Leader | Most outstanding project (2019) AIESEC in University of Sri Jayewardenepura
- Excellence performance in Engineering Technology (2016) Bandaranayake college

#### References

- Dr. Yongliang Qiao [ Research Fellow ] Australian Institute for Machine Learning, University of Adelaide
   Contact: yongliang.qiao@adelaide.edu.au
- Bill Tsouvalas [ Managing Director ] Savvy Finance, Adelaide, Australia Contact: billt@savvy.com.au
- Nipuna Herath [ Senior Software Engineer ] Rio Tinto, Adelaide Contact: Nipuna.herathp1@riotinto.com

Jan 2020